Serdar Karacay

Full Stack Engineer

+44 7864 331165

serdar@spectrumkod.com

♥ Leamington Spa

twitter.com/serdarkaracay

linkedin.com/serdarkaracay

github.com/serdarkaracay

codewars.com/users/serdarkaracay

I have been working for over 10 years of experience in the finance industry as a Full Stack engineer.

I have been developing as a Full Stack engineer on over 10 enterprise financial applications. These applications manage over 10 million per day transactions for business in all processes, from card operations to fraud.

I built a high performance team. I learned some of technical principle, applications.

- Agile methods for Automation culture
- Improved communication, communicate freely at all levels.
- Code Version Management (pull request, future branch, rebase)
- Regular Standups
- Retrospectives
- Pair Programming

Skills

| Years | | | |
|-------------------------|----|--|----|
| .NET C# | 10 | Docker, Kubernetes | |
| Java and Spring Boot | 5 | Jenkins | |
| NodeJS | 5 | AWS Cloud, AWS CDK, Terraform | 2 |
| MS Sql Server, Oracle | 10 | Cucumber, Selenium and Test pipeline | 8 |
| MySql, MongoDB | 4 | Jira, Bitbucket, Confluence | |
| PostgreSql | 2 | OWASP, Pentest | 5 |
| Angular | 5 | Serverless Modernization | 1> |
| VueJS, Kendo UI | 3 | Grafana, Telegraf and Humio, Prometheus | 2 |
| TypeScript | 5 | Blockchain Smart Contract, HardHat | 1< |
| Kafka, Rabbit MQ, Redis | 3 | PCI-DSS, ISO27001 Compliance | 4 |

Experience

SpectrumKod / Full Stack Engineer

Feb 2021 - PRESENT, Learnington

Developed Multitenant Web Application. I integrated Payment Gateways for 9 bank accounts. I have implemented a dynamic pay transaction routing project for retail sector. Via our payment commission calculation process, the project returned on profit about 25,000 dollars a month. Also, I provided this company easier cash management for Buy Now Pay Later (BNPL)

*Technologies: .Net Core C#, VueJS, Unit, Jenkins, Docker, AWS, DynamoDB, Security Certification Compliance

Caasius.com, Full Stack Developer

The easiest loyalty programme in the world. I enabled clients to create loyalty applications via wallet on iPhone and Android.

*Technologies: .Net Core C#, Angular, AWS, Mongo, PostgreSql, Apple and Google wallet integration

Music Design Group, Solution Architect

Migration of over 10 websites managed by the company to AWS.

US Local Bank, Solution Architect

I advisor the Banking-as-a-Service integration of a small medium-sized local investment bank. I provided the migration to the Azure cloud platform.

SkyscendPay, Blockchain Smart Contract Developer

I developed smart contract for invoice collections on Quorum consensus.

Invoices keeping via Quorum. Metadata customer relation therefore, GDPR compliance.

*Technologies: AWS Blockchain Fabric, Chainstack Quorum, HardHat, NodeJS, VueJS, PostgreSql and DevOps process integration.

US and Sweden Bank, Full Stack Developer

I developed crypto selling and buying integration for the bank's existing customers.

*Technologies: .Net Core C#, VueJS, Jenkins, Docker, AWS, Security Certification Compliance, MySql, MongoDB

Central Bank of the Republic of Turkey (CBRT) (Old Name; BKM Bankalararası Kart Merkezi -

Interbank Card Center of Turkey) - Team Lead Engineer

Dec 2016 - Feb 2021, Istanbul

BKM was acquired by CBRT in 2020 Sep.

I worked last 3 years as a Full Stack team leader in the Enterprise Architecture team.

Continuous Transfer of Funds (FAST), Solution Architect

I developed an Instant and Continuous Transfer of Funds (FAST) System. So mean Faster Payments Service (FPS) for the UK.

The Instant and Continuous Transfer of Funds (FAST) System is an immediate payment system where customers can send payment orders 7x24 via system participants.

Over 40 financial corporations using it at the moment.

*Technologies: .Net Core C#, VueJS, Oracle, Test Automation, MySql, Kafka, OpenShift, Kubernetes, Jenkins, Docker, Open API Design, Microservice, PCI-DSS and ISO27001 Compliance, ISO20022 Money Transfer

Identity and Access Management, FullStack Developer

I developed an Internal Identity and Access Management application. Active Directory based user management. Creation of internal and external users of the company with IAM and operation of approval processes.

Users and applications could access all applications within their permissions from one place. So technical means Single Sign On.

*Technologies: Net C# MVC, AngularJS, MS Sql Server, Test Automation, Jenkins, Microservice, PCI-DSS and ISO27001 Compliance

API Gateway, Solution Architect

I developed the standard API system among over 30 big banks. Thus, the bank communicates with other banks through only one institution.

I provided consultancy on the establishment of the interbank joint payment system platform. For example, the use of shared cards and creating a special clearing commission fee between them.

*Technologies: Java Spring Boot, GRPC, Oracle, Test Automation, Jenkins, PCI-DSS and ISO27001 Compliance

I completed the design and development of DevOps processes and the implementation and commissioning of each department into the development environment.

It also specializes in DevSecOps and penetration testing.

Willing to learn new skills and face new challenges in a dynamic work environment.

Verifone / Software Engineer

March 2014 - Dec 2015, Istanbul

In the first eight months, POS (Point of sale) new embedded library I developed using C++, Linux & SqlLite (ISO8583, Security Level).

I developed POS Simulator and managed by configuration with application at remote.

*Technologies: Java and Spring Boot, KendoUI, Oracle, WebSocket, TCP,

Opet / Software Engineer

March 2013 - March 2014, Istanbul

Opet is the energy sector leader in Turkey.

I managed stock exchange applications and maintained.

Standardization of integration among group companies.

I built tool integration service virtualization.

*Technologies: Java, Spring Boot, XML, Kong API gateway, Oracle

Bilsa / Software Engineer

Sep 2010 - Sep 2012, Izmir

Bilsa is a very old company in the education sector. So 1986 since.

I developed a product, at that time, it was called K12-KDS (1 to 12 school level class - Decision Support System).

*Technologies: .Net C#, Asp.Net MVC, Telerik components, Sql Server, Sql Server Reporting Service, SignalR

Product Describe;

Measuring and Assessing Exam

Students and courses can be withdrawn from the central system, no need for manual information entry. By using this product, which we developed to measure the success of the student and the class in the tests and written exams administered by the course teachers at short intervals, to identify the missing parts and to give a make-up education warning if necessary;

You can evaluate the tests and written exams in the school on time and take precautions, you can reach the results of the exam with optical answer sheets in a short time, you can transfer the grades taken after the exam as a written or oral grade with a single click without re-entering the Mixed and Classical system. In addition, you can rank the comparative exam results based on student and class, follow the student's success, class and teacher, and examine the item analysis question success rates.

You can create a FLASH MEMORY for teachers for exam evaluations.

Teachers can evaluate the written exams by scoring them based on questions.

You can send the exam scores to the student or their parents via SMS.

You can automatically send Exam Scores to the E-School system.

Education

Ege University - Computer Engineer / BSc

Dec 2006 - Feb 2010, Izmir Turkey

GPA 3.11/4

Awards

One of my projects in CBRT was nominated to finalists for the 'Best Use of Emerging or Innovative Technology' category in the Banking Technology Awards 2017 awards in London.

Please visit...

https://pbs.twimg.com/media/DQ9Y_tEWkAEMqA4?format=jpg